<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-LEW24447-YNS-NG-KND"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>112 S1171 RS: Ending Trading and Holdings In Congressional Stocks (ETHICS) Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2024-12-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><calendar>Calendar No. 729</calendar><congress>118th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 1171</legis-num><associated-doc role="report">[Report No. 118–309]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20230417">April 17, 2023</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S307">Mr. Brown</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S331">Mrs. Gillibrand</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S363">Mr. King</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S313">Mr. Sanders</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S284">Ms. Stabenow</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S309">Mr. Casey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S422">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S409">Mr. Luján</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S418">Mr. Fetterman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S385">Ms. Cortez Masto</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S354">Ms. Baldwin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S308">Mr. Cardin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S314">Mr. Tester</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S359">Mr. Heinrich</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S353">Mr. Schatz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S402">Ms. Rosen</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S366">Ms. Warren</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00" added-display-style="italic" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><action stage="Reported-in-Senate"><action-date date="20241219" legis-day="20241216">December 19 (legislative day, December 16), 2024</action-date><action-desc>Reported by <sponsor name-id="S380">Mr. Peters</sponsor>, with an amendment</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/131">chapter 131</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, to prevent Members of Congress and their spouses and dependent children from trading stocks and owning stocks, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H5E92552620C74592BF1BE7770D0A65B3"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1" changed="deleted" reported-display-style="strikethrough" committee-id="SSGA00"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Ending Trading and Holdings In Congressional Stocks (ETHICS) Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id1463c2fa0e1745f2a1738bd39d871633" changed="deleted" reported-display-style="strikethrough" committee-id="SSGA00"><enum>2.</enum><header>Placement of certain assets of Members of Congress and their spouses and dependent children in qualified blind trusts</header><subsection id="id52B1830CC17149C8B79601DB954DFBEA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/131">Chapter 131</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idDAF8D9B68001444189150263C538E450" changed="deleted" reported-display-style="strikethrough" committee-id="SSGA00"><subchapter id="idF04F4B4388A840A5BC030A230D93A9CD" style="OLC"><enum>IV</enum><header>Certain assets of Members of Congress and their spouses and dependent children</header><section section-type="subsequent-section" id="id286476D3223C4D979418431243650583"><enum>13161.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this title:</text><paragraph id="id76cfbe39720440f9b644c4af4dc85a14"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Commodity</header><text>The term <term>commodity</term> has the meaning given the term in section 1a of the Commodity Exchange Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1a">7 U.S.C. 1a</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8eab746e0029406f9acf2a0bab48d94c"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered investment</header><subparagraph id="id16C3B454F8ED44478A70ED1DC526D567"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>covered investment</term> means—</text><clause id="idE2008929D4BB46188F056B0268E2202C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an investment in—</text><subclause id="id8EDF374BA7DD4BA3AF01BA9A2D750CAD"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a security;</text></subclause><subclause id="idE4C79B7438B84C969605618A6D7E7E4C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a commodity; or</text></subclause><subclause id="id902A330C331247549E49345D5C20DCFD"><enum>(III)</enum><text>a future; </text></subclause></clause><clause id="idF140CAD6BB7945CBB8F1C6C9AAD3CB9C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any economic interest comparable to an interest described in clause (i) that is acquired through synthetic means, such as the use of a derivative, including an option, warrant, or other, similar means; or</text></clause><clause id="idE74A7624CAFF483490E7F1D1131C8560"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any interest described in clause (i) or (ii) that is held directly, or in which an individual has an indirect, beneficial, or economic interest, through—</text><subclause id="id3D14FF86FC1049EFA72E81E51E39DCEB"><enum>(I)</enum><text>an investment fund or holding company;</text></subclause><subclause id="id4E7E5EB12F8D4D21B365F28D7C9890F5"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a trust (other than a qualified blind trust);</text></subclause><subclause id="idE4A4A1E908BF4D17B276E009A7896561"><enum>(III)</enum><text>an employee benefit plan; or</text></subclause><subclause id="id44F28CAAA4A247BFBB7141AF603AFC70"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>a deferred compensation plan, including a carried interest or other agreement tied to the performance of an investment, other than a fixed cash payment.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2dff214d91184b8595b668226c802376"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusions</header><text>The term <term>covered investment</term> does not include—</text><clause id="id0f9e21b04fa140bd88ab318d9761a03d"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a diversified mutual fund (including any holdings of such a fund);</text></clause><clause id="idA2EAC9394E1045229852A1F3D6209746"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a diversified exchange-traded fund (including any holdings of such a fund);</text></clause><clause id="idB5D06F2C361E405797968FAC12421EF0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a United States Treasury bill, note, or bond;</text></clause><clause id="id48072F238E2A47B0B6C62617313FE7BD"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>compensation from the primary occupation of the spouse of a Member of Congress, or any security that is issued or paid by an operating business that is the primary employer of such a spouse that is issued or paid to such a spouse; </text></clause><clause id="id2B5D84BB0F9F4C5AAA3980731D6CB983"><enum>(v)</enum><text>holding and acquiring any security that is issued or paid as compensation from corporate board service by the spouse of a Member of Congress, including the dividend reinvestment in the same security received from the corporate board service by the spouse of a Member of Congress; </text></clause><clause id="id42B38969D0684F5B9E59954B9242A938"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>any covered investment that is traded by the spouse of a Member of Congress in the course of performing the primary occupation of such a spouse, provided the investment is not owned by a covered person; </text></clause><clause id="idB9BB6998291B4B38BFF11D54F43638C6"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>any investment fund held in a Federal, State, or local government employee retirement plan;</text></clause><clause id="id968FCBFCD76241DE88175AB9DE750DA0"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>a tax-free State or municipal bond; </text></clause><clause id="id05EEC7E14C1149088BFA5F7D02155DF4"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>an interest in a small business concern, if the supervising ethics office determines that the small business concern does not present a conflict of interest, and, in the case of an investment in a family farm or ranch that qualifies as an interest in a small business concern, a future or commodity directly related to the farming activities and products of the farm or ranch;</text></clause><clause id="id82CBC1F916AD45848A0987C4598C7EBA" commented="no"><enum>(x)</enum><text>holding investment-grade corporate bonds, provided that the corporate bonds are held by an individual who is a covered person on the date of enactment of the <short-title>Ending Trading and Holdings In Congressional Stocks (ETHICS) Act</short-title>;</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="id04B3DCCD32F645108D79261320181C46"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>any share of Settlement Common Stock issued under section 7(g)(1)(A) of the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1606">43 U.S.C. 1606(g)(1)(A)</external-xref>); or</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="id0E9EC9B6A7114314B341108C4ED14628"><enum>(xii)</enum><text>any share of Settlement Common Stock, as defined in section 3 of the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1602">43 U.S.C. 1602</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idfe8ef8d498dc47cc93d901a51e361e16"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered person</header><text>The term <term>covered person</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="id317c9a0ef6134fe6ba132ac80a4e6e41"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a Member of Congress; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2ea5bd530ca245af81a1411e26a110ab"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a spouse or dependent child of a Member of Congress. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id7e831052d2f64bc7a2bbc60dab3f8ea7"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Custody</header><text>The term <term>custody</term> has the meaning given the term in section 275.206(4)–2(d) of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of enactment of the <short-title>Ending Trading and Holdings In Congressional Stocks (ETHICS) Act</short-title> or a successor regulation).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5E9796F941D04E27A47C909E593DFE00"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Dependent child</header><text>The term <quote>dependent child</quote> means, with respect to any Member of Congress any individual who is—</text><subparagraph id="idB55A73AA169B42209D29879603628D29"><enum>(A)</enum><text>under the age of 19; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6D8BA666623C47DCB4AA8138BE032C82"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a dependent of the Member of Congress within the meaning of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/152">section 152</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide509faaa69454aab9fc7c73b8db64260" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Diversified</header><text>The term <term>diversified</term>, with respect to a fund, trust, or plan, means that the fund, trust, or plan does not have a stated policy of concentrating its investments in any industry, business, or single country other than the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id8ad60f653c134137a94f0e3935dbbe41"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Future</header><text>The term <term>future</term> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="id1465787AD30C40ECA3609943474AFEDC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a security future (as defined in section 3(a) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78c">15 U.S.C. 78c(a)</external-xref>)); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="idD5F9E8306253491B8FEE446A03AD3E9F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other contract for the sale of a commodity for future delivery.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id889B8FB8F3D84051B3495A37C9DED58A"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Illiquid investment</header><text>The term <quote>illiquid investment</quote> means an interest in a private fund, as defined in section 202(a)(29) of the Investment Advisers Act of 1940 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/80b-2">15 U.S.C. 80b–2</external-xref>). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc36de4022094439d8730c0f5333e0110"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Initial property</header><text>The term <term>initial property</term> means an asset or financial interest transferred to a qualified blind trust by, or on behalf of, an interested party or a relative of an interested party, regardless of whether the asset or financial interest is transferred to the qualified blind trust on or after the date of establishment of the qualified blind trust.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idace3441270634955b2772eec0fd07aea"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Interested party</header><text>The term <term>interested party</term> has the meaning given the term in section 13104(f)(3)(E).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5077f888027740dbba54fa7b2ef8f23b"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Member of Congress; supervising ethics office</header><text>The terms <term>Member of Congress</term> and <quote>supervising ethics office</quote> have the meaning given those terms in section 13101. </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id953babd5ac974f8ebb19fe9be708d221"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Qualified blind trust</header><text>The term <term>qualified blind trust</term> means a qualified blind trust (as defined in section 13104(f)(3)) that has been approved in writing by the applicable supervising ethics office under section 13104(f)(3)(D).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id080ea4e519a7437fbccab35ed50d9e3e"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Security</header><text>The term <term>security</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3(a) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78c">15 U.S.C. 78c(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id160FCA3E6A5444A3B9ADE948E938CBB4"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Small business concern</header><text>The term <quote>small business concern</quote> has the meaning given the term under section 3 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/632">15 U.S.C. 632</external-xref>). </text></paragraph></section><section id="id8CD04813C47D4339AE7449CDE286D0C0"><enum>13162.</enum><header>Trading covered investments</header><subsection id="idfe9180a6b87246f9ac54a29ca9ea86bb"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Ban on trading</header><text>Except as provided in subsections (b) and (c)—</text><paragraph id="id1b0fe78471a246ff8fc774616c53fca4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>effective on the date of enactment of the <short-title>Ending Trading and Holdings In Congressional Stocks (ETHICS) Act</short-title>, a Member of Congress shall not purchase any covered investment;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb2916ea925a846d0946c4b88bdbd1e6f"><enum>(2)</enum><text>effective on the date that is 90 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Ending Trading and Holdings In Congressional Stocks (ETHICS) Act</short-title>, a Member of Congress shall not sell any covered investment, except as provided in section 13163(a)(2); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id42ff8f29d0a5427fb7fdbef1deac09c7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>on and after the effective date described in section 13163(k), a covered person that is a spouse or dependent child of a Member of Congress shall not purchase any covered investment or sell any covered investment, except as provided in section 13163(a)(2).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id901c485e75834ece9bb3e7386ebb46fa" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Optional divestment window</header><text>Notwithstanding subsection (a)—</text><paragraph id="ida7db54495c4d45f5b3a621db180672a7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a Member of Congress who is sworn as a Member of Congress on or before the date of enactment of the <short-title>Ending Trading and Holdings In Congressional Stocks (ETHICS) Act</short-title> may sell a covered investment within 90 days of the date of enactment of such act, provided that the Member of Congress may not sell any covered investment at any time outside of that period while the Member of Congress serves the term for which the Member of Congress was elected or is reelected or appointed as a Member of Congress except as provided in section 13163(a)(2); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3cc590b4223547a5904db3652fb99fc8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a Member of Congress who is sworn as a Member of Congress after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Ending Trading and Holdings In Congressional Stocks (ETHICS) Act</short-title> may sell a covered investment within 90 days of commencing the term of service as a Member of Congress, provided that the Member of Congress may not sell any covered investment at any time outside of that period while the Member of Congress serves the term for which the Member of Congress was elected or is reelected or appointed as a Member of Congress except as provided in section 13163(a)(2). </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="id859767D6F4CB4CD5A4F75C5B9F173F2B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Notwithstanding subsection (a), a covered person may divest a covered investment as directed by the relevant supervising ethics office pursuant to this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="id2cce30741a2644a58c61117725fd3dae"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Joint covered investment</header><text>Any covered investment reported to the supervising ethics office as jointly owned by a Member of Congress and the spouse of the Member of Congress shall be deemed to be a covered investment of the Member of Congress for purposes of this section.</text></subsection></section><section id="idC54E9AE74A7F451FB69659D4D8281193"><enum>13163.</enum><header>Addressing owned covered investments</header><subsection id="id5A666F6839D045718279B9863955828B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Members of Congress</header><paragraph id="idCAD5E3E5F7F140C9AC11CC56E5880DBD" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Certification</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the applicable effective date described in subsection (j), a Member of Congress shall submit to the supervising ethics office a certification, which the supervising ethics office shall publish online that certifies that—</text><subparagraph id="id74D82F9870354932896FC15C15B8893A" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>each covered investment owned by, or in the custody of, the Member of Congress, or a spouse or dependent child of the Member of Congress, will, by the applicable deadline under paragraph (2), be—</text><clause commented="no" id="id92073091E0274D1788543EF95178AE60"><enum>(i)</enum><text>divested, as described in paragraph (2)(B); or</text></clause><clause id="idACC22EA3EB5041DD86C2A4A83E3160CC" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>placed in a qualified blind trust, including through the establishment of a qualified blind trust for that purpose, if necessary, as described in paragraph (2)(A); and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4C7ABB632CB54E2C81C416AC750CA6E1" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>no spouse or dependent child of the Member of Congress owns, or has custody of, covered investments with a cumulative amount equal to more than $10,000, in accordance with paragraph (6). </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id4CAE47025D8241179910C05A8A413ABC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Divestiture or placement in qualified blind trust</header><subparagraph id="idEDCA4E1EEC824D2FB8421C73D2CEF0B7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>Subject to paragraphs (3) and (6) and subsection (b)(2), not later than 120 days after the applicable effective date described in subsection (j), a Member of Congress shall divest, or place in a qualified blind trust (including by establishing a qualified blind trust for that purpose, if necessary), each covered investment owned or in the custody of—</text><clause id="idDEE01F6237DA46E3BDA9222392EB8532"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Member of Congress; or</text></clause><clause id="id6E2EB906DE714A47BD349223848B530E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a spouse or dependent child of the Member of Congress. </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB5CFEE2CA7674346820CCEE1CFE8FDB1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Divestiture</header><text>A covered person shall divest any covered investment owned by or in the custody of the covered person that is not placed in a qualified blind trust not later than the date described in subparagraph (A), subject to any extension granted under paragraph (3). </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idEC04FDBD32634C9CA6F979DB17EF3405"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Qualified blind trusts</header><clause id="id54B267EF046D46278C78DEDFD712724A"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Mandatory sale of initial property in qualified blind trust</header><subclause id="id099A7948C96B4981B6B1C6608F68CA4B"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to clause (ii), if a covered person places, or has placed before the applicable effective date described in subsection (j), 1 or more covered investments in a qualified blind trust, the trustee of the qualified blind trust shall divest any such covered investment not later than the date specified in subclause (II).</text></subclause><subclause id="idFF2206B1957B416780129A110CBF6E62"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Deadline</header><text>The date specified in this subclause is—</text><item id="id2686BC11B54C4B2985E5F026E3470517"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>with respect to a covered investment placed in a qualified blind trust before the applicable effective date described in subsection (j), 120 days after such applicable effective date; and</text></item><item id="idDB6F2BDE629A45D4B382A00E05AFC1A0"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>with respect to a covered investment placed in a qualified blind trust on or after the applicable effective date described in subsection (j), 120 days after the date of creation of the qualified blind trust, as dated by the executed qualified blind trust agreement. </text></item></subclause><subclause id="id3C42BBD625474DDCAD6EBF6F8F66C56B"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Notice of compliance</header><item id="idC6E1FF5C84824CE8A16BD2C37A573736"><enum>(aa)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to item (bb), upon completion of the divestiture of all initial property pursuant to subclause (I)—</text><subitem id="idED7A6349ACFC4BD6982E46AE4A678080"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>the trustee of a qualified blind trust shall submit to the supervising ethics office and each beneficiary of the trust a written notice stating that all initial property of the qualified blind trust has been divested; and </text></subitem><subitem id="id115E07DF82F1483A8F9ED602CCFCEEE5"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>the supervising ethics office shall publish the notice described in subitem (AA) on the website of the supervising ethics office. </text></subitem></item><item id="id983358CA22A54A60884305E5ECF333EF"><enum>(bb)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Each notice described in item (aa)(AA)— </text><subitem id="id797FC31EF6A549848B05C872E32B3829"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>shall only identify the initial property generally by referring to the complete list of assets described in section 13104(f)(5)(A)(ii); and </text></subitem><subitem id="id1175AF7DDB6D431EBBBC29255DBDC836"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>may not contain any other information relating to any holding of the qualified blind trust or the timing of any divestiture. </text></subitem></item></subclause></clause><clause id="idF261B896E68E454FA291BEC26C76D57A"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Extension of mandatory sale of initial property</header><subclause id="idCBC44EBF6E374691925850F025342011"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Request</header><text>A covered person may apply to the supervising ethics office for an extension of the period described in clause (i)(I) if the size or complexity of the covered investments in the qualified blind trust warrant such extension.</text></subclause><subclause id="id981F4A2F95D24165AAE65649E93A63BD"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>An extension granted under subclause (I) shall not exceed 90 days. </text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB993D05BAB6E4245BE0D5D42414C7B8B"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Illiquid investments</header><clause id="idAFC6853EE494433A923E7E391F8A3550"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Sale</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date on which a covered person is contractually permitted to sell an illiquid investment, the covered person shall divest the illiquid investment.</text></clause><clause id="id9876CD2D19804D68816038E46764133E"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>A covered person may not place an illiquid investment in any qualified blind trust under subparagraph (A).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5038B2260A9142F69242540368224638"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Trustees</header><text>A trustee of a qualified blind trust—</text><clause id="id79D618DDC32342D69E35184340540449"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall be required to be a financial institution, as defined in section 1a of the Commodity Exchange Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1a">7 U.S.C. 1a</external-xref>); and </text></clause><clause id="id501FE76A243F4F20AC72F6FC9E2C008C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>except for a financial institution, may not be—</text><subclause id="id36BCF5BE740244438A9D9A7CB2154279"><enum>(I)</enum><text>an attorney; </text></subclause><subclause id="id6084F098DC3845358E92472D27AD37BD"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a certified public accountant;</text></subclause><subclause id="id8DFBBF0D7B674F0DAA22B928C090E4D4"><enum>(III)</enum><text>a broker, as defined in section 3(a) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78c">15 U.S.C. 78c(a)</external-xref>); or </text></subclause><subclause id="id974900333D094F1C8C3FF9BD41E403DD"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>an investment advisor. </text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9CE4F8CF1A99461E85332F2820E9437E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Extension of assets being placed in qualified blind trusts</header><text>If a covered person is unable to place a covered investment in a qualified blind trust by the date described in paragraph (2)(A), the applicable Member of Congress may request, and the supervising ethics office may grant, 1 or more reasonable extensions, subject to the conditions that—</text><subparagraph id="id19785669F0E845F69E060F46BF758399"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the total period of time covered by all extensions granted for the covered investment shall not exceed 150 days; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id05F8D96E6BFB425480866814B3BD0AD9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the period covered by a single extension shall be not longer than 45 days.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id84b098b26ba64cfb828ae71e4c8eeb56"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Communications regarding existing qualified blind trusts</header><subparagraph id="idCB916460AE444520B69AB7D024E3252E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any direct or indirect communication relating to a qualified blind trust in existence on the applicable effective date described in subsection (j) between a trustee of the qualified blind trust and an interested party shall be permissible for purposes of this title if the communication—</text><clause id="ida3c3bbe6e8e348f19961c3e7e562b49c"><enum>(i)</enum><subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id5499999AA63C411DBD6D656197BD0192"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is made—</text><item id="id937643E7BAD24D8AAF0FE18AF8C667DB" indent="up1"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>in writing; and</text></item><item indent="up1" id="id2384F298268045D58938A7F6B19D003D" commented="no"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>not later than 60 days after that effective date;</text></item></subclause><subclause id="id6325629ca15549e98eade0c4ee8df569" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is filed with the applicable supervising ethics office by the person initiating the communication not less than 5 days before the date of the communication; </text></subclause><subclause id="id9b52a038664d4ac48a9caee65ede6406" indent="up1"><enum>(III)</enum><text>relates to a direction or request to the trustee—</text><item id="id5977E684B80943468501CB9805C84251"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>to sell all initial property placed in the qualified blind trust by any interested party; or</text></item><item id="idC2701D8F79284D059677181DDDC2B525"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>to convert all of an asset in the qualified blind trust into an investment other than a covered investment; and</text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="id4016252cdfb643d5b41ae0dade6d9f3f"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is otherwise permitted under section 13104(f)(3)(C)(vi).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idFB9C66CB0D644834A7FD525CC6014815"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Communications between covered persons and trustees relating to all qualified blind trusts</header><subparagraph id="id78E01325148940AABEA8C334A6B80D67"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Notification</header><text>A trustee of a qualified blind trust shall not notify a covered person if—</text><clause id="id9581B8993DEA409392F28DD5CF1F1A91"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the value of the initial property of the qualified blind trust is less than $1,000; or</text></clause><clause id="id91C6910E0C284AAA89CD1ED6353AF18A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the trustee divests any property of the qualified blind trust, other than the initial property required to be divested pursuant to paragraph (2). </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idFE6378F4298E4118A27FA74090B70FEF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Communication</header><clause id="id1BC22F6B817D41138BB7429B0FAA6661"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any communication between a covered person and the trustee of the relevant qualified blind trust—</text><subclause id="idBBA3D59F67E74FC6A1F47EF8E5A9AC62"><enum>(I)</enum><text>shall be in writing; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id216DE8541B164CB8BE480F85A9978943"><enum>(II)</enum><text>submitted and approved in advance of the communication by the supervising ethics office. </text></subclause></clause><clause id="idDC2F2D565C27420EA9D4FD172330D3FF"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>A communication described in clause (i) may not include any information relating to the manner in which funds of the qualified blind trust are invested, including any information relating to—</text><subclause id="id70E47127EB16417C91A65B5EF49B588A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>any company in which the funds are invested; or</text></subclause><subclause id="idCC2651278CD0400892F4BA60CC85B7F0"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any sector in which the funds are invested. </text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id3C12965FCB584B65976A1F18C2266D1C"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Exception for dependents</header><text>A covered person who is a dependent child of a Member of Congress may have a legal guardian hold or trade on behalf of the dependent child 1 or more covered investments provided that the value of the covered investments in total does not exceed $10,000. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id76BB4A808EDC4686B307C4F6D1197461"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Acquisitions during service</header><paragraph id="id31FA5800989A4197AEDD8E5CCA083EE6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2), and any applicable rules issued pursuant to subsection (h)(3), effective beginning on the date of enactment of the <short-title>Ending Trading and Holdings In Congressional Stocks (ETHICS) Act</short-title>, no covered person may acquire any covered investment. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="idF39660C7F2404294A6ECF67B7C7BECDD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Inheritances</header><subparagraph id="idf3bf036bb6644ae7a679e23c0e88c0e4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (B), a covered person who inherits a covered investment shall come into compliance as required under subsection (a) by not later than 120 days after the date on which the covered investment is inherited.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9cc17bc48a6d496db9647910a94b9a7f"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Extensions</header><text>If a covered person is unable to meet the requirements of subparagraph (A), the applicable Member of Congress may request, and the supervising ethics office may grant, 1 or more reasonable extensions, subject to the conditions that—</text><clause id="idb9e5f145d2894dca9cb07c86f1fb1732"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the total period of time covered by all extensions granted for the covered investment shall not exceed 150 days; and</text></clause><clause id="id2aa84d33228e415c8255fded9fcbded2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the period covered by a single extension shall be not longer than 45 days.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idec2df5d5d30d4550a0f7671340092a69"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Family trusts</header><paragraph id="id664269875310411db9340f41899d7d23" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A supervising ethics office may grant an exemption for a family trust only if—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="idC853FCF11AD24AB18D5C51314E9ED2D4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>no covered person—</text><clause id="id616ad365c3cd4c139819808be75b8a0e" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is a grantor of the family trust;</text></clause><clause id="id78c5512f5cd3497fb18b111f9d8b8a51" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>contributed any asset to the family trust; or</text></clause><clause id="idc963e824f5fa4f88a564284cb509ea8e" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>has any authority over a trustee of the family trust, including the authority to appoint, replace, or direct the actions of such a trustee; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id69DA3FB94E19436B80ABE0B731A7FCDC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the grantor of the family trust is or was a family member of the covered person. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id035a98fc6f6d487487a1af37a93da022"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requests</header><text>A covered person seeking an exemption under paragraph (1) shall submit to the applicable supervising ethics office a request for the exemption, in writing, certifying that the conditions described in that paragraph are met.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9c2b780d0e08407fafc97d2f00aada82"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>A supervising ethics office shall publish on the public website of the supervising ethics office—</text><subparagraph id="ida45ec0255b4643fd9874a80ee85cee8c"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a copy of each request submitted under paragraph (2); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfdba13de4d6e4f4c83612144c9c0ee53"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the written response of the supervising ethics office to each request described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4d3b405438e644de812e50065a9cba60"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Mingling of assets</header><text>A spouse or dependent child of a Member of Congress may place a covered investment in a qualified blind trust established by the Member of Congress under subsection (a)(2)(A)(i).</text></subsection><subsection id="ide58c8479c73945ba9269d4de81b32107" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Separation from service and cooling-Off period required for control</header><text>During the period beginning on the date on which an individual becomes a Member of Congress and ending on the date that is 90 days after the date on which the individual ceases to serve as a Member of Congress, the Member of Congress, and any spouse or dependent child of the Member of Congress, may not—</text><paragraph id="id936CFA15507446979EA30F7C0156ED45" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>dissolve any qualified blind trust in which a covered investment has been placed pursuant to subsection (a)(2); or </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id10A2C0EBE9C54C71A705D07E06F72C39" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>except as provided in this section, otherwise control a covered investment, including purchasing new covered investments. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ide4e1431fb07443488523d244efced86c"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header><paragraph id="id1EAD75AEA63D4CF5AFCEB002A4499827"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Supervising ethics offices</header><text>Each supervising ethics office shall make available on the public website of the supervising ethics office—</text><subparagraph id="id73F74E43EF8D40248DB3DB1F6CF9A16D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a copy of—</text><clause id="id27357287EC7B41FC91C36989F8FC14A8" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>each certification submitted to the supervising ethics office under subsection (a)(1);</text></clause><clause id="id7c40054aeb71441f9d9162ad838fbe05"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>each qualified blind trust agreement of each covered person;</text></clause><clause id="id9F623707950B47FE957FA6525FC50FA8"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>each notice and other documentation submitted to the supervising ethics office under this section; and</text></clause><clause id="id38eb051e588d4460b38993ea486897c6"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>each notice, ruling, and other documentation issued or received by the supervising ethics office under subsection (c);</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id577ebef1cbec484ab8845a96cab33e13"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a schedule of all assets placed in a qualified blind trust by each covered person and interested party; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbbd97b4c7da14b5dbc2a4958a0e67e15"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a description of each extension granted, and each civil penalty imposed, pursuant to this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idBAC0F4643F114527986D867D0BCD4175"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Trustees</header><text>Each trustee of a qualified blind trust established by a covered person shall submit to the covered person and the applicable supervising ethics office a written notice in any case in which the trustee learns that an interested party has obtained knowledge of any trust property other than the initial property of the qualified blind trust. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id16010dc3e8794aa290f654d1f300b99d"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Member of Congress</header><text>Each Member of Congress who is a beneficiary of a qualified blind trust shall submit to the applicable supervising ethics office—</text><subparagraph id="iddb9b78ab2c3041d5a99f2eb2467ec8c8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a copy of the executed qualified blind trust agreement by not later than 30 days after the date of execution;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfece16040be74a86a5b132cf7114c6ef"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a list of each asset and each financial interest transferred to the qualified blind trust by an interested party by not later than 30 days after the date of the transfer;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idDBF5578B376E4EA7ADD7F1B33399FDF4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a copy of each notice submitted to the Member of Congress under paragraph (2) by not later than 30 days after the date of receipt;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3391bc3eccde4e24a5fb7f3a55298561"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a written notice that an interested party has obtained knowledge of any holding of the qualified blind trust by not later than the date that is 30 days after the date on which the Member of Congress discovered that the knowledge had been obtained; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id99a16a9fdc894581978355175fc38af9"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a written notice of dissolution of the qualified blind trust by not later than 30 days after the date of dissolution.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5123C9AD976B44E09B6C9F4B2D650A3C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Federal benefits</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id014808FED7B043FB9969FC7807B726F0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Covered payment</header><text>In this paragraph, the term <term>covered payment</term>—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idA547614F076B4D0FB4784491C71DF80A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>means a payment of money or any other item of value made, or promised to be made, by the Federal Government;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0F061E3E0E0E4310AE0167665A252BD1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6D8CD749634846228130ED8C30E3B7C9"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a loan agreement, contract, or grant made, or promised to be made, by the Federal Government, including such an agreement, contract, or grant relating to agricultural activity; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3E3793A0B9ED4EAE9941A3E7E93E2963"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such other types of payment of money or items of value as the supervising ethics office may establish, by guidance; and</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3AB4F3EEFD06437E80D69091EEE6D4C9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>does not include—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3B949A18D510422EB759375A8ED01F19"><enum>(I)</enum><text>any salary or compensation for service performed as, or reimbursement of personal outlay by, an officer or employee of the Federal Government; or</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id18E1BA497FF8408A806ED849FECE60E5"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any tax refund (including a refundable tax credit).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idD27D1B392B6D4E7680933590894A2107"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Reporting requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of receipt of a notice of any application for, or receipt of, a covered payment by a covered person (including any business owned and controlled by the covered person), but in no case later than 45 days after the date on which the covered payment is made or promised to be made, the covered person shall submit to the applicable supervising ethics office a report describing the covered payment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id8c8652124fb6426fb88edb1903bbcf7d"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><paragraph id="idf9cf394f21504ed3b731dae91cd258a0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Divestiture or placement in qualified blind trust</header><subparagraph id="idb9605ef7690e4116a034616e5b84d7c6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The applicable supervising ethics office shall provide a written notice (including notice of the potential for civil penalties under subparagraph (B)) to any Member of Congress if the Member of Congress, or spouse or dependent child of the Member of Congress—</text><clause id="id5C92C62C8C9A4A07A0FBBAD00C49FB85"><enum>(i)</enum><text>fails to submit a certification under subsection (a)(1) by the date on which the certification is required to be submitted; </text></clause><clause id="idF04C29871FE94577AE32687342638F99"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>fails to divest or place in a qualified blind trust a covered investment owned by, or in the custody of the covered person, in accordance with subsection (a)(2), subject to any extension under subsection (a)(3); or</text></clause><clause id="id596857B2A92F478495B075222D7F138A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>acquires an interest in a covered investment in violation of this section.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide2915236de374a6e953a1cfb929ae30d"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Civil penalties</header><clause id="ide6f6bb587e684c6896b8d411e24e1c28"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the event of continuing noncompliance after issuance of the notice described in subparagraph (A), the supervising ethics office shall impose a civil penalty, in the amount described in clause (ii), on a Member of Congress to whom a notice is provided under clause (i) or (ii) of subparagraph (A)—</text><subclause id="id728fe9930be04acb9d6306d249895081"><enum>(I)</enum><text>on the date that is 30 days after the date of provision of the notice; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id1680cfdcf97a46cf8c3e30cca4d2ea40"><enum>(II)</enum><text>during the period in which such noncompliance continues, not less frequently than once every 30 days thereafter.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="idc39a3c7ca9074deab4eacffef426005e"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Amount</header><text>The amount of each civil penalty imposed on a Member of Congress pursuant to clause (i) shall be equal to the greater of—</text><subclause id="id1f4d81386cf543a285d30a50701f36c9"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the monthly equivalent of the annual rate of pay payable to the Member of Congress; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id6231df695da34fa7aba9774f5792d658"><enum>(II)</enum><text>an amount equal to 10 percent of the value of each covered investment that was not divested or placed into a qualified blind trust in violation of this section during the period covered by the penalty.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idb68f5182af614624a4071a7fcd3745ac"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Communications</header><text>The Attorney General of the United States shall file a civil action seeking to impose a civil penalty on any covered person or trustee of a qualified blind trust who violates subsection (a)(4), or otherwise discloses the contents of a qualified blind trust to any unauthorized individual, equal to the greater of—</text><subparagraph id="id9dc43c3eaba54ec7bacc5c77e95dcd9f"><enum>(A)</enum><text>$10,000 per each communication; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id086f8eb0a6a2411bb4973e3a783bb27f"><enum>(B)</enum><text>1 percent of the value of the qualified blind trust on the date of the violation. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id5a2d308a661e4caab404ad2b3540ed2c" commented="no"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Duties of supervising ethics offices</header><text>Each supervising ethics office in the legislative branch shall—</text><paragraph id="id385e842e53d649baa35ff2e2359f6dc7" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>impose and collect civil penalties in accordance with subsection (g);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id48b4e6dff7714e51a43ff0785b13197c" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>establish such procedures and standard forms as the supervising ethics office determines to be appropriate to implement this section;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc1d513a1dcdf40d7b2a260f28e684ea8" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>issue such rules and guidelines as the supervising ethics office determines to be appropriate for the implementation and application of this title; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd4ce5774480445d6ba61c903199c88a5" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>publish on a website all documents and communications described in this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id113494695F3A4CE6B83FE50F0F9F9787" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to prevent a covered person from owning or trading—</text><paragraph commented="no" id="id8B8977E937754AFFA54018688BA300BE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a diversified mutual fund; or </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idD062745FFBD24B21A7E5EC39F7E529A7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a publicly traded, diversified exchange traded fund.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="idFF5ACBD7D2D7434DB19102E93D7D967E"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This section shall apply to each covered person beginning on the date on which the covered person (or with respect to a covered person that is a spouse or dependent child of a Member of Congress, the date on which that Member of Congress) commences the first new term of service as a Member of Congress on or after January 31, 2023.</text></subsection></section></subchapter><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4679c105da344ea1a92148120ac489e1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/131">chapter 131</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="USC" id="idc089c7ae-27e7-43d3-b7fa-ebb827aff68a" changed="deleted" reported-display-style="strikethrough" committee-id="SSGA00"><toc changed="deleted" reported-display-style="strikethrough" committee-id="SSGA00"><toc-entry level="subchapter">SUBCHAPTER IV—Certain assets of Members of Congress and their spouses and dependent children</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section">13161. Definitions. </toc-entry><toc-entry level="section">13162. Trading covered investments</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section">13163. Addressing owned covered investments</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="idC98B8F81D4EC42808D354946DC54A3BE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendments</header><paragraph id="H648FBADE4F2046E988A7FA1D6D90192A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Title 5</header><text>Title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida4cb93b640ee493e986033846fd8d356"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 13103(f)—</text><clause id="H4184F22B7D3E4E899B877AD160ED3E4C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in paragraph (9), by striking <quote>as defined in section 13101 of this title</quote>;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE39DB5BDAC814854AFE5F689A9A255F5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (10), by striking <quote>as defined in section 13101 of this title</quote>;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB029AF892AA54AD3B62D29CB9374760B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (11), by striking <quote>as defined in section 13101 of this title</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="HF646954782E14D52801600D128B827ED" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (12), by striking <quote>as defined in section 13101 of this title</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="id670AEB294B5D486DB2AE9FCA3E5D3BF6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in section 13122(f)(2)(B)—</text><clause display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="id37FE9B4187B74827BCABC79BEBB2660D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Subject to clause (iv) of this subparagraph, before</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>Before</quote>; and</text></clause><clause display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="id4DD55C7CF129401A9EAA2EA435798C95"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking clause (iv).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H69A78E439C564602A60437499D906F4D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995</header><text>Section 3(4)(D) of the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1602">2 U.S.C. 1602(4)(D)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>legislative branch employee serving in a position described under section 13101(13) of title 5, United States Code</quote> and inserting <quote>officer or employee of Congress (as defined in section 13101 of title 5, United States Code)</quote>. </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6A95A580F86A4E6296D1CFCFA75DF463"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Securities Exchange Act of 1934</header><text>Section 21A of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78u-1">15 U.S.C. 78u–1</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H16C4CDC796B04FE1B34A2F922C7DF5D2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (g)(2)(B)(ii), by striking <quote>section 13101(11)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 13101</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0C6A22D3C3FB458EB65B612E6C3AC74F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (h)(2)—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFE52FA4A9E474A96BF21945DFA8804B7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>in section 13101(9)</quote> and inserting <quote>under section 13101</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="H70262377D160409BBC0E2FA4D9B125D6" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>section 13101(10)</quote> and inserting <quote>in section 13101</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idADA209345E2948688C3FD20C3B842DAF" commented="no" changed="deleted" reported-display-style="strikethrough" committee-id="SSGA00"><enum>3.</enum><header>Penalty for STOCK Act noncompliance</header><subsection id="id41641745176c4dfca241ba9a3cc1d4d8" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Fines for failure To report</header><paragraph commented="no" id="id6D4810C1CFFF455AB7B91B7F3A2F33F2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The STOCK Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/112/105">Public Law 112–105</external-xref>; 126 Stat. 291) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8bed8d028d5240bab2f24ac23cadbfeb" changed="deleted" reported-display-style="strikethrough" committee-id="SSGA00"><section id="idb90f2ee188584b05a221f8947290543b" commented="no"><enum>20.</enum><header>Fines for failure to report</header><subsection id="id85f2e10474024c41b8cffbe1dfdfe2c2" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law (including regulations), a reporting individual shall be assessed a fine, pursuant to regulations issued by the applicable supervising ethics office (including the Administrative Office of the United States Courts, as applicable), of $500 in each case in which the reporting individual fails to file a transaction report required under this Act or an amendment made by this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="idc3a813a54ed247fbb9ea7af6169fc114" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Deposit in Treasury</header><text>The fines paid under this section shall be deposited in the miscellaneous receipts of the Treasury.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idE7D394596FA14B0BB0117D6473E197AA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by paragraph (1) shall take effect on the date on which the reporting individual who is a Member of Congress commences the first new term of service as a Member of Congress on or after January 31, 2023. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="iddc318bb4b325479fb4089822f6384da2" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rules, regulations, guidance, and documents</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, each supervising ethics office (as defined in section 13101 of title 5, United States Code) (including the Administrative Office of the United States Courts, as applicable) shall amend the rules, regulations, guidance, documents, papers, and other records of the supervising ethics office in accordance with the amendment made by this section.</text></subsection></section><section id="id08DCA7C6E25B4FBABC2984D7F0D0F584" commented="no" changed="deleted" reported-display-style="strikethrough" committee-id="SSGA00"><enum>4.</enum><header>Electronic filing and online public availability of financial disclosure forms</header><subsection id="id531d393c77a14e6d80b063edc8463000" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Members of Congress and congressional staff</header><text>Section 8(b)(1) of the STOCK Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/13107">5 U.S.C. 13107</external-xref> note) is amended—</text><paragraph id="idb175f78d2ea54cd4b042f4af656787e3" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by inserting <quote>, pursuant to subchapter I of chapter 131 of part IV of title 5, United States Code, through databases maintained on the official websites of the House of Representatives and the Senate</quote> after <quote>enable</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd988116492e646378ac7451c82c76aca" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (B) and the undesignated matter following that subparagraph and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida7f8f3a0715c4377b1e10f6057200ea6" changed="deleted" reported-display-style="strikethrough" committee-id="SSGA00"><subparagraph id="idd0803da29b494a29a210a052b0b9e630" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>public access—</text><clause id="id3ea45452b70044a5b53f85b3c28dc536" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to each—</text><subclause id="id6c55713ecb0340c5be55cc7e4906f101" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>financial disclosure report filed by a Member of Congress or a candidate for Congress;</text></subclause><subclause id="id22e539b089e74bad88d4d37e98dff777" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>transaction disclosure report filed by a Member of Congress or a candidate for Congress pursuant to subsection (l) of that section; and</text></subclause><subclause id="idff3ead0ca1f94571941055e7b2836578" commented="no"><enum>(III)</enum><text>notice of extension, amendment, or blind trust, with respect to a report described in subclause (I) or (II), pursuant to subchapter I of chapter 131 of part IV of title 5, United States Code; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id4bea3e603ec840b9bc1ffa71c50978e5" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in a manner that—</text><subclause id="id059a7755eb3f4da8bdce7eafb2cc82fc" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>allows the public to search, sort, and download data contained in the reports described in subclause (I) or (II) of clause (i) by criteria required to be reported, including by filer name, asset, transaction type, ticker symbol, notification date, amount of transaction, and date of transaction;</text></subclause><subclause id="id19f41c1f327d43bdb4c9cf7757e3578a" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>allows access through an application programming interface; and</text></subclause><subclause id="ide66a6f9c734f4577ae6636b3b21bb8eb" commented="no"><enum>(III)</enum><text>is fully compliant with—</text><item id="id9b8d18dac9db4255aebbd4f549401c45" commented="no"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>section 508 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/794d">29 U.S.C. 794d</external-xref>); and</text></item><item id="id247840a584954eb9af4817444a20d612" commented="no"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the most recent Web Content Accessibility Guidelines (or successor guidelines).</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id7abd688291434a3aacf16d5de43e9ce7" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section take effect on the date that is 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="id30B8A851335D48B397F008365CEEA004" changed="deleted" reported-display-style="strikethrough" committee-id="SSGA00"><enum>5.</enum><header>Severability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any provision of this Act, an amendment made by this Act, or the application of such provision or amendment to any person or circumstance is held to be unconstitutional, the remainder of this Act and of the amendments made by this Act, and the application of the remaining provisions of this Act and amendments to any person or circumstance, shall not be affected. </text></section></legis-body><legis-body display-enacting-clause="no-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="idf842012b-ef1f-40d9-8170-7f1fd54428ef" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="SSGA00"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Ending Trading and Holdings In Congressional Stocks (ETHICS) Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="ida2790a0f-161d-4b65-9487-e9923cb9f053" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="SSGA00"><enum>2.</enum><header>Divestment of certain assets of Members of Congress, the President, the Vice President, and their spouses and dependent children</header><subsection id="iddf64c4f7-bf96-4844-ada9-baa407ea15a9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/131">Chapter 131</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id17f02767-b4bf-4a17-81f9-0d25324bda7e" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="SSGA00"><subchapter id="idccbe53d9-5744-4cdb-bfdd-ee13201f6a30" style="OLC"><enum>IV</enum><header>Certain assets of Members of Congress, the President, the Vice President, and their spouses and dependent children</header><section section-type="subsequent-section" id="ide9ba2c1e-1ad0-45f2-9c21-ae4a60ccb5c1"><enum>13161.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this subchapter:</text><paragraph id="id2a5e4546-4070-417e-94f4-1549df05a941"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Commodity</header><text>The term <term>commodity</term> has the meaning given the term in section 1a of the Commodity Exchange Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1a">7 U.S.C. 1a</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id31be46de-f4af-4d1d-bee1-373b9e641b68"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered investment</header><subparagraph id="id31e306ad-084c-4d91-9b88-b9aced0a251b"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>covered investment</term> means—</text><clause id="id60f912fe-1234-449b-8698-56df655e2cb9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an investment in—</text><subclause id="idf4755969-74c6-4980-951e-52fdada7407b"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a security;</text></subclause><subclause id="id1f6fd5c2-029f-453f-b039-023a5fa68af7"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a commodity; </text></subclause><subclause id="id003ada91-68cd-4b8e-b07d-5007093db00a"><enum>(III)</enum><text>a future; or</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id39570097a7004fe285361d46b703b51f"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>a digital asset;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id945bea92-eac2-45ab-833a-e0ae36b79926"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any economic interest comparable to an interest described in clause (i) that is acquired through synthetic means, such as the use of a derivative, including an option, warrant, or other similar means; or</text></clause><clause id="idb1bf1155-aa63-4b29-b81c-87ee37097037"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any interest described in clause (i) or (ii) that is held directly, or in which an individual has an indirect, beneficial, or economic interest, through—</text><subclause id="idec62b574-0a1f-41ab-abc0-1fd92675e63c"><enum>(I)</enum><text>an investment fund or holding company;</text></subclause><subclause id="id399438d1-accc-4fd5-a544-0788ce7b1bab"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a trust;</text></subclause><subclause id="idaf0d9776-9376-4412-9188-1872903bede6"><enum>(III)</enum><text>an employee benefit plan; or</text></subclause><subclause id="idf79cfa23-efd0-49b8-8fbd-fb722824097a"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>a deferred compensation plan, including a carried interest or other agreement tied to the performance of an investment, other than a fixed cash payment.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb2cc900e-1118-4332-9586-0d66760d9217"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusions</header><text>The term <term>covered investment</term> does not include—</text><clause id="id4ca1d0ff-d3f8-4765-8068-7d0b56c12fa8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a diversified mutual fund (including any holdings of such a fund);</text></clause><clause id="id016b0178-f343-4397-8568-28d875fb3c93"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a diversified exchange-traded fund (including any holdings of such a fund);</text></clause><clause id="ide9301796-e7ea-4ca3-9e2d-5c50e2c39e44"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a United States Treasury bill, note, or bond;</text></clause><clause id="id92c6c17b-6438-4137-9cd7-e454dc9abfd7"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>compensation from the primary occupation of the spouse of a covered person, or any security that is issued or paid by an operating business that is the primary employer of such a spouse that is issued or paid to such a spouse; </text></clause><clause id="ide52fe494-cec2-488d-b7fc-3f69f04bf153"><enum>(v)</enum><text>holding and acquiring any security that is issued or paid as compensation from corporate board service by the spouse of a covered person, including the dividend reinvestment in the same security received from the corporate board service by the spouse of a covered person; </text></clause><clause id="id25cb5b2d-31cc-4ba3-80ce-bdd2b6fba53b"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>any covered investment that is traded by the spouse of a covered person in the course of performing the primary occupation of such a spouse, provided the investment is not owned by a covered person or the spouse or dependent child of a covered person; </text></clause><clause id="id2bcd4756-793b-4a43-a108-fc37eabdf31e"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>any investment fund held in a Federal, State, or local government employee retirement plan;</text></clause><clause id="idd466d81e-4589-4971-9308-a9353ee104ed"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>a tax-free State or municipal bond; </text></clause><clause id="idbda0d663-2a50-4ec4-8b56-15978673677d"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>an interest in a small business concern, if the supervising ethics office determines that the small business concern does not present a conflict of interest, and, in the case of an investment in a family farm or ranch that qualifies as an interest in a small business concern, a future or commodity directly related to the farming activities and products of the farm or ranch;</text></clause><clause id="id58706578-e2b2-4ede-9325-68a9aff94ad0" commented="no"><enum>(x)</enum><text>holding investment-grade corporate bonds, provided that the corporate bonds are held by an individual who is a covered person, or a spouse or dependent child of a covered person, on the date of enactment of the <short-title>Ending Trading and Holdings In Congressional Stocks (ETHICS) Act</short-title>;</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="idab5e7fbd-eec9-4304-8797-a48b9756eb5d"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>any share of Settlement Common Stock issued under section 7(g)(1)(A) of the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1606">43 U.S.C. 1606(g)(1)(A)</external-xref>); or</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="idf24d582f-7fb8-42ac-819f-68d694aa39fa"><enum>(xii)</enum><text>any share of Settlement Common Stock, as defined in section 3 of the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1602">43 U.S.C. 1602</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id66524b5ab20d48b4a8b3755f4436548c"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed to imply that particular digital assets are not securities, commodities, or other types of covered investments. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id7584f7e9-b409-4dfd-a8e3-0b44103c046c"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered person</header><text>The term <term>covered person</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="id38a88d3a-b534-42e3-8f1d-bfadf9e1ea3e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a Member of Congress;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id34794a42-a134-4fd9-8af4-9a2fc0a36887"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the President of the United States; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id25295bde26264f1b9015dc6ad6be051f"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Vice President of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id55fdb3ec-e847-4495-a789-a23d5ec679b4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Custody</header><text>The term <term>custody</term> has the meaning given the term in section 275.206(4)–2(d) of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on the date of enactment of the <short-title>Ending Trading and Holdings In Congressional Stocks (ETHICS) Act</short-title> (or any successor regulation). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3ab8b862-e1d2-4044-abf8-247eacf9220b"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Dependent child</header><text>The term <quote>dependent child</quote> means, with respect to any covered person, any individual who is—</text><subparagraph id="ida2b9b13d-53da-45c5-9c71-5b4e85d4c999"><enum>(A)</enum><text>under 19 years of age; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2de883b1-73c6-4715-9f64-9369a1548fac"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a dependent of the covered person within the meaning of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/152">section 152</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id2dda14d2ea814836b7c6e4eb1a8dfac7"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Digital asset</header><text>The term <term>digital asset</term> means any digital representation of value that is recorded on a cryptographically secured distributed ledger or any similar technology. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6027f8d0-0806-40e5-b2ed-17be017ac2c2" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Diversified</header><text>The term <term>diversified</term>, with respect to a fund, trust, or plan, means that the fund, trust, or plan does not have a stated policy of concentrating its investments in any single industry, business, or single country other than the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id9a320712-caf6-4513-b660-925703c18fab"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Future</header><text>The term <term>future</term> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="id50a61d38-cb34-4ee8-9a88-de840694d0ab"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a security future (as defined in section 3(a) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78c">15 U.S.C. 78c(a)</external-xref>)); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="idd8c6034d-62c5-4c54-8eb4-93b8826592d0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other contract for the sale of a commodity for future delivery.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id01e2f951-5ebb-41c7-a5f8-1e07f9f06d5f"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Illiquid investment</header><text>The term <term>illiquid investment</term> means an interest in a private fund, as defined in section 202(a) of the Investment Advisers Act of 1940 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/80b-2">15 U.S.C. 80b–2(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide7ed6b04-14fc-4a6e-9610-eb9e4d694f6c"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Interested party</header><text>The term <term>interested party</term> has the meaning given the term in section 13104(f)(3)(E).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida4893a53-e53c-4076-8bf0-62b60a06c957"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Member of Congress; supervising ethics office</header><text>The terms <term>Member of Congress</term> and <quote>supervising ethics office</quote> have the meanings given those terms in section 13101. </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id473315f9-7896-41df-ab3c-287a530f27d2"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Qualified blind trust</header><text>The term <term>qualified blind trust</term> has the meaning given the term in section 13104(f)(3).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id641c139d-5743-41fa-a00a-add5b6d6ef5d"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Security</header><text>The term <term>security</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3(a) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78c">15 U.S.C. 78c(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idad68a86b-e9f2-4ac5-95a0-68d4a66add72"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Small business concern</header><text>The term <quote>small business concern</quote> has the meaning given the term under section 3 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/632">15 U.S.C. 632</external-xref>). </text></paragraph></section><section id="idacd77939-ee88-45c9-8de6-71926ab09d82"><enum>13162.</enum><header>Trading covered investments</header><subsection id="ida55b484f-c802-4d4a-b7c5-99ee75c9437f"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Ban on trading</header><text>Except as provided in subsections (b) and (c)—</text><paragraph id="idf2423c34-f7e8-49af-96d3-5eb7fad7c149"><enum>(1)</enum><text>effective on the date of enactment of the <short-title>Ending Trading and Holdings In Congressional Stocks (ETHICS) Act</short-title>, a covered person shall not purchase any covered investment;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide0bc7382-ca82-4fb4-8c74-cccf30b61313"><enum>(2)</enum><text>effective on the date that is 90 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Ending Trading and Holdings In Congressional Stocks (ETHICS) Act</short-title>, a covered person shall not sell any covered investment, except as provided in section 13163(a)(1); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2093f0db-72b1-4dda-979c-a7025f6d0f76"><enum>(3)</enum><text>on and after the effective date described in section 13163(j), an individual who is a spouse or dependent child of a covered person shall not purchase any covered investment or sell any covered investment, except as provided in section 13163(a)(1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id1988a655-64d9-471d-a69c-8122be2bf292" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Optional divestment window</header><paragraph id="id90197d49-8948-4736-8e34-61f1767c4611"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Current Members</header><text>Notwithstanding subsection (a), a covered person who is sworn into office on or before the date of enactment of the <short-title>Ending Trading and Holdings In Congressional Stocks (ETHICS) Act</short-title> may sell a covered investment within 90 days of the date of enactment of such Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id115ba2f2-022f-4e0b-905e-3a636f4988b7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>New Members</header><text>Notwithstanding subsection (a), a covered person who is sworn into office after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Ending Trading and Holdings In Congressional Stocks (ETHICS) Act</short-title>, but before the effective date under section 13163(j), may sell a covered investment within 90 days of commencing a new non-consecutive term of service as a Member of Congress, President, or Vice President.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="id3365cb66-af5d-4773-86b7-1085d7c34d11"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Notwithstanding subsection (a), a covered person may divest a covered investment as directed by the relevant supervising ethics office pursuant to this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="id02bb91f5-9258-4bcd-851a-fb74e7c50836"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Joint covered investment</header><text>Any covered investment reported to the supervising ethics office as jointly owned by a covered person and the spouse of the covered person shall be deemed to be a covered investment of the covered person for purposes of this section.</text></subsection></section><section id="idfed3d286-560c-4857-b9cf-91fcbe359051"><enum>13163.</enum><header>Addressing owned covered investments</header><subsection id="id214a2a73-8fd5-4594-a91d-c35e40e9fa44"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Covered persons</header><paragraph id="id69801d05-93f0-42df-871d-b866d3d7b9c7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Divestiture</header><subparagraph id="id4f826551-cab4-4dee-9bbe-37281b91a651"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Requirements</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbbc059d803484dd59964143ffe566416"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Officials sworn in before the effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to paragraph (2) and the amendments made under subsection (b), a covered person who is sworn into office on or before the effective date described in subsection (j), not later than 120 days after the effective date described in subsection (j), subject to any extension granted under subparagraph (C)(iii) of this paragraph, shall divest each covered investment owned or in the custody of—</text><subclause id="idbbad1982-eb11-4cbc-a9af-2614771b19e9"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the covered person; or</text></subclause><subclause id="id2e4b58fd-13b5-4f74-8660-20a8b558ed07"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a spouse or dependent child of the covered person. </text></subclause></clause><clause id="id7e5b6dffca72446f81e6a964d2b6cc12"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Officials sworn in after the effective date</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2) and the amendments made under subsection (b), a covered person who is sworn into office after the effective date described in subsection (j), not later than 120 days after commencing a new non-consecutive term of service as a Member of Congress, President, or Vice President, subject to any extension granted under subparagraph (C)(iii) of this paragraph, shall divest each covered investment owned or in the custody of—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id07a1c6350c544a11ab7e155e014c2b92"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the covered person; or</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2eac0a6b22fb4afebc3ee14c4bed0649"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a spouse or dependent child of the covered person.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9c1655daf21a42adb3f8262a9e732197"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Illiquid investments</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date on which a covered person is contractually permitted to sell an illiquid investment, the covered person shall divest the illiquid investment. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc1907515a47c487dbe10d1e007f42d16"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Qualified blind trusts</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfadddfff57b74c56a7f410185eb1729f"><enum>(i)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Prohibition on future qualified blind trusts</header><text>Except as provided in clause (iii), on and after the date that is 180 days after the effective date described in subsection (j), no covered person, or the spouse or dependent child of the covered person, may maintain a qualified blind trust.</text></clause><clause id="id3788fbf4f7c24736a15689bf125ce26b"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Mandatory sale of covered investments in existing qualified blind trusts</header><subclause id="id607168ccb833442faff3ea42f1c91fd8"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The trustee of a qualified blind trust holding covered investments shall, at a time elected by the covered person, on behalf of a covered person, and in accordance with clause (iv)—</text><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0950c466d2f2408c920d22472ee85dbf"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">divest all covered investments held in the qualified blind trust for the purposes of complying with the divestiture requirements under this section, in accordance with subparagraph (A); and</text></item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id025abeb96b304c9b810380be6d8659d7"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>dissolve the qualified blind trust in accordance with this chapter and guidance from the supervising ethics office. </text></item></subclause><subclause id="idac477c2da4f04a2d9d7de0138e00134c"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Notice of compliance</header><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1e626b5ce80a4490b35f432a7706eca4"><enum>(aa)</enum><header>Notice of divestiture</header><subitem commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb68b65f7745f4fa1a37ecd2c6a8d360d"><enum>(AA)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon the completion of divestiture of all covered investments pursuant to subclause (I)(aa), the trustee shall submit to the supervising ethics office and the applicable covered person a written notice stating that the trustee has completed divestiture of all covered investments held in the qualified blind trust pursuant to subclause (I)(aa).</text></subitem><subitem id="id6caada1401d84fb0adce56a2dd524e85"><enum>(BB)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>The supervising ethics office shall publish the notice required under subitem (AA) on the website of the supervising ethics office. </text></subitem></item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id69b7a3d6ab7140ce9d23ef4ae7acba70"><enum>(bb)</enum><header>Notice of dissolution</header><text>Upon the dissolution of a qualified blind trust pursuant to subclause (I)(bb), the trustee shall submit to the supervising ethics office and the applicable covered person a written notice stating that the trust has dissolved the qualified blind trust pursuant to subclause (I)(bb) and shall include a list of the assets held in the qualified blind trust on the date of the dissolution of such trust and the category of value of each such asset.</text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="idb2891f33ecf64d6caa695cc6461439f3"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Extension of mandatory sale of covered investments</header><subclause id="id6d2e4fa749124c29b0ae45c98a295f2a"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Request</header><text>Each covered person who maintains a qualified blind trust established by the covered person, or a spouse or dependent child of the covered person, in any case in which the trustee of the qualified blind trust believes the size or complexity of the covered investments in the qualified blind trust warrant such extension may apply to the supervising ethics office for an extension of the period described in subparagraph (A).</text></subclause><subclause id="idfee3dd0fb1ae408e913141625c96b97d"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>An extension granted under subclause (I) shall not exceed 90 days.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="idc4600c5604764836abc78efdfdeb0f61"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Communications</header><text>A covered person may communicate with and direct the trustee of their qualified blind trust for the purposes of—</text><subclause id="id8b7dc783b8e3459685d4cd2c06d936f2"><enum>(I)</enum><text>determining when divestment of covered investments in the qualified blind trust should occur, pursuant to paragraph 1(A) of this subsection, clause (ii) of this subparagraph, or section 13162(b), as applicable; </text></subclause><subclause id="idedd071f5ae8844de8d90671e56b327f9"><enum>(II)</enum><text>determining which permitted property covered investments should be divested into; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id4b77409373004db89b8563bffb57fd13"><enum>(III)</enum><text>whether the trustee utilizes a certificate of divestiture pursuant to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/1043">section 1043(b)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as amended by subsection (b) of this section. </text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id22d3679e-ea83-4fbc-a415-ca6b5a33e27d"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception for dependents</header><text>An individual who is a dependent child of a covered person may have a legal guardian hold or trade on behalf of the dependent child 1 or more covered investments provided that the value of the covered investments in total does not exceed $10,000. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id9d2e780e41a1472696cfe5ee8fe925f5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Tax treatment of divestitures</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id87c315db6b3b463ba754209b7475fbae"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/1043">Section 1043(b)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc44abbd0ce9346ccb968cf9e32f86cbe"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)(A), by inserting <quote>or a covered person (as defined in section 13161 of title 5, United States Code),</quote> after <quote>of the Federal Government,</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfd6f5caf9c2347d7bf6c4eff5c25f3f4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)(B)—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6c9f1b17cb9d4fc6ba5f67db6f319b46"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>employees, or</quote> and inserting <quote>employees,</quote>; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfad30f667d0247c4897f50a51710cf69"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting <quote>or the applicable supervising ethics office (as defined in section 13101 of title 5, United States Code), in the case of a covered person</quote> after <quote>judicial officers,</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id748b329e7e164514b5637613af7e4e9b"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>or any diversified investment fund approved by regulations issued by the Office of Government Ethics</quote> and inserting <quote>, any diversified investment fund approved by regulations issued by the Office of Government Ethics (in the case of any eligible person who is not a covered person (as defined in section 13161 of title 5, United States Code)), or any diversified mutual fund or a diversified exchange-traded fund described in clause (i) or (ii) of section 13161(2)(B) of title 5, United States Code (in the case of any eligible person who is a covered person (as so defined)).</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb2cd46a561d34d38b06c30f84a1f107f"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this subsection shall apply to sales after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Ending Trading and Holdings In Congressional Stocks (ETHICS) Act</short-title>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idab191622d93f4da49b2c30da65b5e373"><enum>(c)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Acquisitions during service</header><paragraph id="id74a2980f-c8d9-48e8-84bc-f1465fe21235"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2), and any applicable rules issued pursuant to subsection (h)(3), effective beginning on the date of enactment of the <short-title>Ending Trading and Holdings In Congressional Stocks (ETHICS) Act</short-title>, no covered person, or spouse or dependent child of a covered person, may acquire any covered investment. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6964a049-1e71-4004-b63f-333cdda0bae7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Inheritances</header><subparagraph id="id6270d10b-a6e5-4316-8c32-ce562b299fc1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (B), a covered person, or a spouse or dependent child of a covered person, who inherits a covered investment shall come into compliance as required under subsection (a) by not later than 120 days after the date on which the covered investment is inherited.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id673981ff-1278-4e2b-a6ff-f4836e56d5c2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Extensions</header><text>If a covered person, or a spouse or dependent child of a covered person, is unable to meet the requirements of subparagraph (A), the applicable covered person may request, and the supervising ethics office may grant, 1 or more reasonable extensions, subject to the conditions that—</text><clause id="ida3dac16f-6a06-4680-afff-feef68c24ea3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the total period of time covered by all extensions granted for the covered investment shall not exceed 150 days; and</text></clause><clause id="idb9a53656-7e52-44e2-bb17-24b45bcf07bf"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the period covered by a single extension shall be not longer than 45 days.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id171c57a5-71a0-4260-ac8f-9688711ad816"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Family trusts</header><paragraph id="id51debc91-0e50-4896-a603-7dbcb2bd3b08" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A supervising ethics office may grant an exemption for a family trust only if—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="ide9aaf9cb-ddce-4ba7-8aae-e9231e95ffa9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>no covered person, or spouse or dependent child of a covered person—</text><clause id="id5286f323-a50a-489f-8e58-1a2f5ae866c9" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is a grantor of the family trust;</text></clause><clause id="id51d1b97e-bf6b-463b-b1c5-56627c981aa1" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>contributed any asset to the family trust; or</text></clause><clause id="idd370a171-046c-4cce-a923-89961f19c321" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>has any authority over a trustee of the family trust, including the authority to appoint, replace, or direct the actions of such a trustee; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id5f748acb-2358-46f8-8e83-247401988de8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the grantor of the family trust is or was a family member of the covered person, or the spouse or dependent child of the covered person. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id56a8dd04-9e01-4873-918e-0587239e4cd1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requests</header><text>A covered person seeking an exemption under paragraph (1) shall submit to the applicable supervising ethics office a request for the exemption, in writing, certifying that the conditions described in that paragraph are met.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id48e624fd-3514-4c90-bc49-a99eddf859ce"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>A supervising ethics office shall publish on the public website of the supervising ethics office—</text><subparagraph id="id576b0707-e1db-4ef3-8ce6-32d7819362bf"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a copy of each request submitted under paragraph (2); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf725ab31-53b7-4c35-8fd1-415eab2ff353"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the written response of the supervising ethics office to each request described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id3d2045a0-963b-41ef-a1d3-82f031a78243" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Separation from service and cooling-off period required for control</header><text>During the period beginning on the date on which an individual becomes a Member of Congress, President, or Vice President and ending on the date that is 90 days after the date on which the individual ceases to serve as a Member of Congress, President, or Vice President, the covered person, and any spouse or dependent child of the covered person, may not, except as provided in this section, otherwise control a covered investment, including purchasing new covered investments. </text></subsection><subsection id="ida329c5f5-d49a-4a16-97eb-bd91c989e47e"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header><paragraph id="id8c5fc02a-584b-4a23-8212-6480dae840a7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Supervising ethics offices</header><text>Each supervising ethics office shall make available on the public website of the supervising ethics office—</text><subparagraph id="idb03df899-18e6-4a9e-a05a-6137a3f4566e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a copy of—</text><clause id="id38071efa-fb0a-4cb4-ad30-37ed3582ad97" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>each notification submitted to the supervising ethics office in accordance with subsection (a)(1)(C)(ii)(II);</text></clause><clause id="idf02a9104-58c4-4886-8eed-da6ccb960ddc"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>each notice and other documentation submitted to the supervising ethics office under this section; and</text></clause><clause id="idee4cca9f-7db1-453d-a6ac-b61a64062d81"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>each written response and other documentation issued or received by the supervising ethics office under subsection (d); </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf30e41c5fefa48a68ec3bbb2baa06b7b"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 30 days after a qualified blind trust maintained by a covered person is dissolved, a written notice of the dissolution of the qualified blind trust; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id916f31ff-f927-436a-8013-9101934d8df0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a description of each extension granted, and each civil penalty imposed, pursuant to this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idb7cca97f-4f3b-4d26-85ea-573ab434bdfc"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federal benefits</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3ed7b3a4-105f-4e3f-9208-d401a68f765f"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Covered payment</header><text>In this paragraph, the term <term>covered payment</term>—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfef00ff5-f51a-4b90-9673-24e40c8f0aac"><enum>(i)</enum><text>means a payment of money or any other item of value made, or promised to be made, by the Federal Government;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6e487fab-bdf3-4b52-b452-c22dfd424b47"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc4ea9ff3-6273-4b7c-961d-af7922ca7425"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a loan agreement, contract, or grant made, or promised to be made, by the Federal Government, including such an agreement, contract, or grant relating to agricultural activity; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id96f8bb77-839d-47dc-bc7a-780ca9f18961"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such other types of payment of money or items of value as the supervising ethics office may establish, by guidance; and</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7be09b1a-55bc-4a65-8485-f26780492bbe"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>does not include—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida217bf84-8319-4c2e-807c-2188c1df34ce"><enum>(I)</enum><text>any salary or compensation for service performed as, or reimbursement of personal outlay by, an officer or employee of the Federal Government; or</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6b2fe190-85b7-4d12-96b0-f7f175674cd5"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any tax refund (including a refundable tax credit).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3ce4886c-9eb4-4366-b701-afe94e497e6c"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Reporting requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of receipt of a notice of any application for, or receipt of, a covered payment by a covered person, or a spouse or dependent child of a covered person, (including any business owned and controlled by the covered person, spouse, or dependent child), but in no case later than 45 days after the date on which the covered payment is made or promised to be made, the covered person shall submit to the applicable supervising ethics office a report describing the covered payment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id2d5db4fd-2a88-42fb-b34e-76126f83ba9b"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><paragraph id="id20180511-b6ce-47db-ac99-2075046ef3c3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The applicable supervising ethics office shall provide a written notice (including notice of the potential for civil penalties under paragraph (2)) to any covered person if the covered person, or the spouse or dependent child of the covered person, as applicable—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id09789510c05348df9229f58812ae6d48"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">fails to divest a covered investment owned by, in the custody of, or held in a qualified blind trust of, the covered person or spouse or dependent child of a covered person, in accordance with subsection (a)(1), subject to any extension under subsection (a)(1)(C)(iii); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id218ad44d-0b83-463e-9554-e4160653c0da"><enum>(B)</enum><text>acquires an interest in a covered investment in violation of this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idb9c8a2f9-816e-44a4-b292-a5d8293e92dc"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Civil penalties</header><subparagraph id="idfbfe8543-da2a-4452-99d6-3863d558fef1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the event of continuing noncompliance after issuance of the notice described in paragraph (1), the supervising ethics office shall impose a civil penalty, in the amount described in subparagraph (B), on a covered person to whom a notice is provided under subparagraph (A) or (B) of paragraph (1)—</text><clause id="id4b35318a-6fd6-4ae9-97d2-8328faf00045"><enum>(i)</enum><text>on the date that is 30 days after the date of provision of the notice; and</text></clause><clause id="id4efbeacb-5b08-4b07-ab99-fb236394628e"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>during the period in which such noncompliance continues, not less frequently than once every 30 days thereafter.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id337d58ae-c321-4e03-b315-b58dcd1cec73"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Amount</header><text>The amount of each civil penalty imposed on a covered person pursuant to subparagraph (A) shall be equal to the greater of—</text><clause id="id5a13cb41-8953-4fa3-bf95-822333504331"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the monthly equivalent of the annual rate of pay payable to the covered person; and</text></clause><clause id="idd6cfef94-a42e-4a63-950e-7a397f2f4288"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an amount equal to 10 percent of the value of each covered investment that was not divested in violation of this section during the period covered by the penalty.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id9bc3f9af-72c5-4350-aa23-db89e603e4ab" commented="no"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Duties of supervising ethics offices</header><text>Each supervising ethics office shall—</text><paragraph id="id61a8f724-f85e-4cde-ba41-33636a5746d3" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>impose and collect civil penalties in accordance with subsection (g);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id05956827-9b05-47a3-8c4f-62c5a3e23d0a" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>establish such procedures and standard forms as the supervising ethics office determines to be appropriate to implement this section;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7ddf6509-a8bb-4935-9b03-3c41ddaaa590" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>issue such rules and guidelines as the supervising ethics office determines to be appropriate for the implementation and application of this title; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id697b065f-2986-4850-9ba6-d641516b5abc" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>publish on a website all documents and communications described in this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id5179ae1f-cb53-4ecb-8853-6f30f38fd4da" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to prevent a covered person, or a spouse or dependent child of a covered person, from owning or trading—</text><paragraph commented="no" id="id5af7521f-39e0-49b7-9c7c-9225bbde0843"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a diversified mutual fund; or </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id7098ef65-b634-40dc-a281-7d42cfc1d58d"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a publicly traded, diversified exchange traded fund.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="id2fa43bea-65c4-43e6-9854-7d574d8d5096"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (c)(1), this section shall apply on and after March 31, 2027.</text></subsection></section></subchapter><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id078fe844-c837-4093-ac99-01e9f12959f2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/131">chapter 131</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="USC" id="id297c04c8-8f52-4494-8138-58720c8c333b" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="SSGA00"><toc changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="SSGA00"><toc-entry level="subchapter">SUBCHAPTER IV—Certain assets of Members of Congress, the President, the Vice President, and their spouses and dependent children</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section">13161. Definitions. </toc-entry><toc-entry level="section">13162. Trading covered investments</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section">13163. Addressing owned covered investments</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="ida1c08af4-f18e-4df7-b450-65df531dd5ed"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendments</header><paragraph id="id8b503a9d-2e41-40d9-af11-5a6fd7d32bd3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Title 5</header><text>Title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide7c7aa00-aef7-4a28-af64-6d54f8fbd827"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 13103(f)—</text><clause id="id167eca4b-eaa1-4d9b-a3d2-16486d949dfa"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in paragraph (9), by striking <quote>as defined in section 13101 of this title</quote>;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id798836b7-5698-4798-81cb-48cc71bdbaea"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (10), by striking <quote>as defined in section 13101 of this title</quote>;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id94295cce-8d58-4bc3-8cab-b6ccfe176eb9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (11), by striking <quote>as defined in section 13101 of this title</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="id5359ac5c-096d-4db4-b7b1-6c97baff14ac" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (12), by striking <quote>as defined in section 13101 of this title</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="idc7964084-3611-4bcb-9b73-caa2c2ecb1ba"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in section 13122(f)(2)(B)—</text><clause display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="id2ad76c49-5083-4fd2-a11a-28fb6123d0e9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Subject to clause (iv) of this subparagraph, before</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>Before</quote>; and</text></clause><clause display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="id9d3aa4fe-1f98-4fcb-bb35-f88231c01d87"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking clause (iv).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idad9f6d9b-b49f-449d-960d-2d185da5b3d9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995</header><text>Section 3(4)(D) of the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1602">2 U.S.C. 1602(4)(D)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>legislative branch employee serving in a position described under section 13101(13) of title 5, United States Code</quote> and inserting <quote>officer or employee of Congress (as defined in section 13101 of title 5, United States Code)</quote>. </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8a54e7ac-b4ec-4d31-aac4-153d57f969f2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Securities Exchange Act of 1934</header><text>Section 21A of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78u-1">15 U.S.C. 78u–1</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb1d4c59d-5d84-403f-a805-2f082c66af06"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (g)(2)(B)(ii), by striking <quote>section 13101(11)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 13101</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4750256a-bf72-4379-b132-8e4c50f5c49f"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (h)(2)—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4107fa6d-3ad9-4eb0-93ea-cc009134798c"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>in section 13101(9)</quote> and inserting <quote>under section 13101</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="id2cbe9626-a693-449e-b295-eea0bf83d2d6" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>section 13101(10)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 13101</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id0b7ddf94-54ce-4dfa-993d-85f93c0bf771" commented="no" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="SSGA00"><enum>3.</enum><header>Penalty for STOCK Act noncompliance</header><subsection id="id6e89a92c-bdf3-4334-aa8e-2c13ebd2fe10" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Fines for failure to report</header><paragraph commented="no" id="id68756b73-765f-4dbe-b1f5-eacf485490d2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The STOCK Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/112/105">Public Law 112–105</external-xref>; 126 Stat. 291) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0cb6f343-8fdf-48b8-9e56-c98571921aec" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="SSGA00"><section id="iddb03ac7b-5989-49cc-b24c-f1e9794788d5" commented="no"><enum>20.</enum><header>Fines for failure to report</header><subsection id="id082d9fff-dbe4-45fd-aa0b-7427e0c8477d" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law (including regulations), a reporting individual shall be assessed a fine, pursuant to regulations issued by the applicable supervising ethics office (including the Administrative Office of the United States Courts, as applicable), of $500 in each case in which the reporting individual fails to file a transaction report required under this Act or an amendment made by this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="id5908cb76-4e00-40ba-8de5-ec0213d830a5" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Deposit in Treasury</header><text>The fines paid under this section shall be deposited in the miscellaneous receipts of the Treasury.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="id0bc23669efae4d489c9532d87b8ea0e9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by paragraph (1) shall apply on and after March 31, 2027.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id84ecae8e-56e1-47ee-9c8a-a0e0dfd74189" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rules, regulations, guidance, and documents</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, each supervising ethics office (as defined in section 13101 of title 5, United States Code) (including the Administrative Office of the United States Courts, as applicable) shall amend the rules, regulations, guidance, documents, papers, and other records of the supervising ethics office in accordance with the amendment made by this section.</text></subsection></section><section id="id38b92c4e-fb75-453f-a14e-aa997d94850d" commented="no" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="SSGA00"><enum>4.</enum><header>Electronic filing and online public availability of financial disclosure forms</header><subsection id="id09b8c05f-4946-47ef-a992-60a90a77e44b" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Members of Congress and congressional staff</header><text>Section 8(b)(1) of the STOCK Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/13107">5 U.S.C. 13107</external-xref> note) is amended—</text><paragraph id="idd12dbc4f-853c-462b-b691-7308256ede92" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by inserting <quote>, pursuant to subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/131">chapter 131</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, through databases maintained on the official websites of the House of Representatives and the Senate</quote> after <quote>enable</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id110cead0-933b-4da7-b5b5-aa60e8d677a6" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (B) and the undesignated matter following that subparagraph and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id94d6b291-0561-4a26-9bda-25f538201280" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="SSGA00"><subparagraph id="id087b7ea1-51b0-4c09-8292-5c2b35197e15" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>public access—</text><clause id="id03d0979f-a3f5-4d13-add5-ef4910fb0bb1" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to each—</text><subclause id="id97eb18ff-9802-478e-bca4-8767ff8edde3" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>financial disclosure report filed by a Member of Congress or a candidate for Congress;</text></subclause><subclause id="id365a4cac-b155-401e-a47d-7bc0c8d4637f" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>transaction disclosure report filed by a Member of Congress or a candidate for Congress pursuant to subsection (l) of that section; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id4a753fa8-7caa-4c7d-acfb-dff14fd8083d" commented="no"><enum>(III)</enum><text>notice of extension, amendment, or blind trust, with respect to a report described in subclause (I) or (II), pursuant to subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/131">chapter 131</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="idb4992aeb-b29e-48a6-8de9-2d57e5151dcd" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in a manner that—</text><subclause id="idafae9d7b-e87f-4ac4-8fed-4efeeed64bb6" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>allows the public to search, sort, and download data contained in the reports described in subclause (I) or (II) of clause (i) by criteria required to be reported, including by filer name, asset, transaction type, ticker symbol, notification date, amount of transaction, and date of transaction;</text></subclause><subclause id="id6796d853-ecf9-4d02-9377-f1c666e15786" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>allows access through an application programming interface; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id6ebd79bd-4990-43eb-ab1c-88e0f867dfb1" commented="no"><enum>(III)</enum><text>is fully compliant with—</text><item id="id9c4f4063-669e-4b62-9bdf-91733f771cdb" commented="no"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>section 508 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/794d">29 U.S.C. 794d</external-xref>); and</text></item><item id="id5ffe9463-447f-41fa-bc3e-ae5ca1a81c39" commented="no"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the most recent Web Content Accessibility Guidelines (or successor guidelines).</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id7f2b2355-f362-4091-aed3-dd6cb824cdf1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall take effect on the date that is 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="idc65630e8-c79c-4ea2-9100-bb89a2d1a95a" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="SSGA00"><enum>5.</enum><header>Severability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any provision of this Act, an amendment made by this Act, or the application of such provision or amendment to any person or circumstance is held to be unconstitutional, the remainder of this Act and of the amendments made by this Act, and the application of the remaining provisions of this Act and amendments to any person or circumstance, shall not be affected. </text></section></legis-body><endorsement><action-date date="20241219" legis-day="20241216">December 19 (legislative day, December 16), 2024</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

